这是一所军事学院
THOMAS LASKY: This is a military academy.
他们在教我们，嗯，如何打仗
They're, uh, teaching us how to fight.
我的哥哥，是这里毕业的
My older brother, he trained here.
你知道，他很优秀的
You know, he was quite popular.
他是很多老师最喜欢的学生
He was a lot of the teachers' favorites.
有时候我觉得很孤独
MICHAEL SULLIVAN: There are times I do get lonely,
但我也交了一些朋友
but I made a couple friends.
社交方面，我觉得
WALTER VICKERS: Socially, I don't think
我还没适应过来
I fit in all too well.
我叫托马斯·拉斯基，我是初级学员
My name is Thomas Lasky, and I'm a Cadet Freshman.
在这所学院受训很辛苦
The Academy's tough in itself.
学业要求严格，气氛也非常严肃
It's such a strict and hostile environment.
我们正在学习如何在一场战斗中
We're trying to learn how to go in and battle
有效地消灭敌人
and essentially kill somebody.
我叫迈克尔·苏利文，我是初级学员
My name is Michael Sullivan, and I'm a Freshman Cadet.
我们受训是为了与叛军作战
We're training to fight insurrectionists.
我想我是在追随我父亲的足迹
I guess I'm following the footsteps of my dad.
至少我是这么想的，我从没见过他
At least I think so. I've never met him.
我爸爸是梅瑟利武器公司的首席财务官
WALTER: My father is a chief financial advisor
我是注定要来到这里的
at Mezriah Weapons.
I was always supposed to come here.
这都是家里为我计划好的
It was always something that had been planned for me.
我叫沃特·韦克斯，初级学员
Walter Vickers, Freshman Cadet.
我叫艾普莉·奥瑞斯基
My name is April Orenski.
我是高级学员
I am a Senior Cadet.
我是哈斯塔提小队的队长
I am the squad leader for Hastati Squad.
我很希望能够在UNSC的军队里找到自己的位置
I was really looking for a place where I can serve the UNSC,
科布罗学院是最好的军校
and Corbulo Academy is the best.
一切对我来说都很新鲜
I'm so new to everything.
你看，我不是在这种环境下长大的
You know, I wasn't raised in this kind of environment,
我还在适应着这一切…
so I'm still trying to...
我试着融入这个环境
I'm trying to fit in.
我叫陈俊杰
My name is JunJie Chen.
我是初级学员
I'm a Freshman Cadet.
我叫凯勒·席尔瓦，我是初级学员
I'm Chyler Silva, and I'm a Freshman Cadet
刚刚加入科布罗军事科学学院
at Corbulo Academy of Military Science.
我好像一直都想加入军队
I sort of always knew that I wanted to be military.
在我10岁的时候，我妈妈就教我如何端起步枪
My mum taught me how to hold a rifle when I was 10.
这里的训练，是我未来人生规划的一部分
DIMAH TCHAKOVA: This training, it's part of who I am about to become.
我必须做该做的事情，走在人生的前面
I have to do what I have to do to get ahead in life.
我叫迪玛·切科娃
My name is Dimah Tchakova.
我是初级学员
I'm Freshman Cadet.
挺辛苦的，但我想，这种团队式的训练会有帮助吧
SULLY: It's been kind of hard, but I think structure guides people.
我想是很难，但太艰苦？
WALTER: I think it's hard, but too severe?
不，我觉得还不是太艰苦
No, I don't think it's too severe.
如果要说的话，就是还不够艰苦
If anything, it's not severe enough,
而且我们在战争中处于劣势
and I don't think we're winning,
我想我们需要竭尽全力、不择手段去争取胜利
and I think we need to do everything possible to win.
这不是游戏
CHYLER: It's not a game.
是让你活下来的训练
It's training for life.
我必须做到最好，因为我相信能够赢得这场战争
I need to be good at this, because I believe in this war.
我开始想我们能否简单地解决这些问题
THOMAS: I'm starting to think that we could sort these things out
而不必去打仗，去杀害那些无辜的人
without going into battle and killing innocent people.
但在学校我不能说那样的话
I can't really say stuff like that at this school,
因为那样做大家都会笑话我的
because people kind of laugh at me,
而且他们会欺负我
and they kind of bully me a bit.
我对叛军怎么看？
WALTER: What do I think of the insurrectionists?
我想他们都是自私的人
I think they're selfish.
屠杀那些手无寸铁的人是不对的
You don't kill people who aren't even fighting.
It's not right.
我就是在叛军一次又一次的袭击中长大的
CHYLER: I grew up around a lot of Innie violence,
他们的目标不仅仅是军事目标
and not just violence towards military targets.
我那里的平民们都不得不学会保护自己
Civilians where I lived really had to learn how to protect themselves.
作为队长意味着我是他们的领袖
APRIL: Being a squad leader means I am their leader.
我要为他们负责
I'm responsible for them.
在背后，他们叫我「机器人」，不过我不介意
They call me "The Robot" behind my back, but I don't mind.
能以一个科布罗学员、一个UNSC战士的方式来做事
I'm proud to do things the Corbulo way, the UNSC way.
我感到很骄傲
我觉得我们不是一定要适应环境的
WALTER: I don't think we're supposed to fit in
或者一定要交朋友
or necessarily make friends,
我们只要团结一致、努力训练
as long as we work together and we work hard
完成肩负的使命即可
and we do what we're supposed to do.
如果是那样的话，我觉得我还算适应的
In that sense, I feel like I fit in great.
我觉得我注定要来到这里
I feel like I'm meant to be here.
我哥哥一直认为我会成为一名优秀的士兵
THOMAS: My brother always thought I'd be a good soldier.
作为一名士兵，并不是毫无原则地使用暴力
CHYLER: Being a soldier isn't about mindless violence.
你需要清醒的头脑
You need a clear head,
谈到叛军，杀戮只是一部分
and given the insurrectionists, killing is part of that.
我能够下手杀人么？
SULLY: Would I be able to take another life?
能吧，我能下手杀人的
WALTER: Yeah, I'd be able to kill.
毕竟，不是你杀人就是被人杀
After all, it's kill or be killed.
我真的觉得自己还没有准备好去打仗
THOMAS: I don't really feel like I'm ready to go into battle.
我想我根本就杀不了人
I don't think I could kill another human being ever.
(Hatches opening)
(Indistinct announcements on P.A.)
求救！求救！求救！
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE: Mayday, Mayday.
这里是UNSC FFG-201，黎明号
This is UNSC FFG-201 Forward Unto Dawn,
要求立即疏散
requesting immediate evac.
舰上有幸存者
Survivors aboard.
优先登船码为V05-3-S0117
Prioritization code Victor zero five dash three
（额定人数：782；存活人数：1）
dash Sierra zero one one seven.
求救！求救！求救！
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
这里是UNSC FFG-201，黎明号
This is UNSC FFG-201 Forward Unto Dawn,
要求立即疏散，舰上有幸存者
requesting immediate evac. Survivors aboard.
有人在听么？
CORTANA: Is anyone listening?
我们已经漫无目的地在太空中漂浮了
We've been floating aimlessly in space
1651天6小时又19分
for 1,651 days, 6 hours, and 19 minutes.
那并不意味着…
That doesn't mean...
船上4年多的时间，一直无所事事
Over four years aboard this ship with nothing to do,
什么任务都没完成
no tasks to complete.
过去的四年里，我做的唯一一件事，就是思考
For over four years, all I have done is think.
(air escaping)
(overlapping frightened voices)
四年时间，我只有思考
CORTANA: (conversing with herself) For four years, all I've done is think.
(equipment beeping)
你在那里做着什么梦呢？
What are you dreaming in there?
我恨你
I hate you.
科塔娜!
Cortana!
别说了！我已经决定了！
Stop it! I've made up my mind!
如果我要在这条船上死去
If I'm going to die aboard this ship,
那么士官长也要和我一样经历这种痛苦
then Chief will suffer the same fate as me.
科塔娜，别这么想
Cortana, stop.
你为他牺牲了一切！
You sacrificed everything for him!
控制住你自己！
Control yourself!
我做不到
I can't.
这样是不对的，怎么…
This isn't right. Something...
(static, screams)
科塔娜，别想了
Cortana, stop.
(voices bleeding through static)
坚持住！
Hold on!
(Static)
有东西让我们慢下来了
Something slowed us down...
某种东西，很有趣
some thing. Interesting.
我需要思考一下
I need to think.
你就是被思考杀死的！
Thinking is what's killing you!
我无法识别它
I don't recognize it.
我记不起来…
I can't remember...
自己的很多事情了
so much of myself.
(gas hissing)
我迷失了
I'm lost.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
(explosion)
喂？谁在哪儿？
Hello? Who's there?
看起来是个外星物体
It appears to be an alien construct.
数据显示它不是星盟建造的
The data confirms it was not built by the Covenant.
不需要更多的分析了
There's no need for more analyzing.
我们处于危险之中
(alarm sounding) - We are in danger.
你说过：「当你需要的时候叫醒我」
Wake me when you need me, you said.
(Metal creaking)
片名：《光晕4 黎明号》
S0117
COMPUTER VOICE: (on recording) Sierra zero one one seven,
求救！求救！求救！
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
这里是UNSC FFG-201，黎明号
This is UNSC FFG-201 Forward Unto Dawn,
要求立即疏散，舰上有幸存者
requesting immediate evac. Survivors aboard.
已锁定频率，正在获取坐标
MAN: Locked onto frequency. Grabbing coordinates.
V05-3-S0117
COMPUTER VOICE: Victor zero five dash three dash Sierra
zero one one seven.
正在处理
MAN: Processing now.
请重放一遍
Play it again, please.
求救，求救，求救
COMPUTER VOICE: Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
这里是UNSC FFG-201，黎明号
This is UNSC FFG-201 Forward Unto Dawn,
要求立即…
requesting immediate...
(overlapping voices shouting on recording)
还需要再播放一遍吗，长官？
MALE COMPUTER VOICE: Shall I play it again, sir?
长官？
Sir?
拉斯基舰长？
Commander Lasky?
(Pods unsealing with a hiss)
(coughing)
生化冷冻舱开启中
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE: Cryopods opening.
(coughing)
拉斯基？你还好么？
Lasky? You okay?
你还好么？
(gasping)
CHYLER: Are you all right?
拉斯基，我们走！
Lasky, let's go!
哈斯塔提小队，4分钟到会合点！
WALTER: (on radio) Hastati Squad, four minutes to rendezvous point!
收到，韦克斯！4分钟！
Copy, Vickers! Time of four minutes!
你那双手能开枪么？
Will you be able to shoot with those hands?
咱们走着瞧
We'll find out.
走啊！
CHYLER: Come on!
Axios!
(Chyler shouting orders)
(Coughing, sound distorted)
拉斯基，快，快走！
SULLY: Lasky, come on, let's go!
(panting)
敌方火力密集！
SULLY: We're under heavy fire!
向会合点前进！
LASKY: Head for the checkpoint!
掩护！
Cover it!
前进！
Move it!
注意掩护！中途点到了！
Aah!
CHYLER: Take cover! Checkpoint!
好，中途点，50秒
THOMAS: Okay, checkpoint, 50 seconds.
走！
Go!
席尔瓦，苏利文，拉斯基
WALTER: (on radio) Silva, Sullivan, Lasky,
你们去哪儿了？
where are you guys?
15秒内抵达会合点，你们准备好了？
RV in 15 seconds! You ready?
庆祝的时候见
I'll see you at the party.
(gunshot) - Aah!
小苏！
Sully!
我们必须继续前进！
We have to leave him!
拉斯基，搞什么飞机？
WALTER: (on radio) Lasky, what the hell?
快走!
CHYLER: Come on!
拉斯基！
WALTER: Lasky!
10秒！
(coughs) 10 seconds!
伤亡：苏利文
(Beeping)
拉斯基，快走！
WALTER: Lasky, hurry up!
马上抵达，3，2，1！
THOMAS: Landing, 3, 2, 1!
敌人来袭，35秒内遭遇
JJ: Enemy inbound. They'll be on us in 35 seconds.
检查武器弹夹，准备进攻
Fresh magazine in your weapon, prepare to attack.
什么？
What?
我们的目标是消灭叛军
Our objective is to neutralize the insurrectionists
并拿下目标
and acquire the target.
听我的指挥行动
We move on my mark.
30秒
JJ: 30 seconds.
我们应该从侧翼包抄，迫使他们投降
We should flank them and force a surrender.
太靠近了，没法包抄的，再说他们也是绝对不会投降的！
They're too close to flank, and looies never surrender!
迪玛和我可以绕过去
Dimah and I could circle round.
还有时间
There's still time.
我们可以做到的
We can make it.
还有25秒，怎么办？
25 seconds. Guys?
这是最好的策略
It's the best move.
20秒
JJ: 20 seconds.
听着，我们还是按照原计划行动，明白？
Look, we're sticking to my plan, okay?
- 听我的指挥 - 行不通的
- On my mark. - It won't work.
你已经不是指挥了，拉斯基！
You're not in charge any more, Lasky!
汤姆，就听他的吧
Tom, just do what he says.
15秒
JJ: 15 seconds.
这是我的命令
They're my orders.
我不管
I don't care.
10秒！
JJ: Ten seconds!
5秒！
Five seconds!
Axios!
拉斯基！
Lasky!
(panting)
(gunshot) - Aah!
哈斯塔提小队队长出列
COMPUTER VOICE: Hastati Squad Leader on the field.
训练暂停
Exercise paused.
让我猜猜看，拉斯基
APRIL: Let me guess, Lasky.
你无视命令
You ignored orders.
报告长官，这只是战略上的一个小小伤亡
It's just another strategic casualty, sir.
不可接受
Unacceptable.
(gunshot) (groans)
训练结束
COMPUTER VOICE: Game over.
学员们，枪上肩
Shoulder your weapon, Cadet.
你的小聪明让哈斯塔提小队
Your little escapade kept Hastati Squad
无法达到训练任务目标…
from achieving its objective...
(coughing)
而且是又一次
Again.
干得好，拉斯基
JJ: Great job, Lasky.
(Groans)
训练完成
COMPUTER VOICE: Exercise complete.
哈斯塔提训练队员，零胜
Zero wins, Hastati defaults.
该死
Shit.
（UNSC 科布罗 野外营地 7-NNE）
机器人盯上你了？
SULLY: The Robot tag you?
是啊，一次从2米远开枪，两次是1米远
Yeah, once from two meters, twice from one.
那些眩晕弹打得我现在还晕乎乎的呢
SULLY: I'm still numb from all those stun rounds.
我一直都晕乎乎的
I'm always numb.
哈斯塔提，举-枪！
APRIL: Hastati, port arms!
布莱克将军，请指示！
General Black, sir!
让我提醒你们这些学员，这所学院的名字
Let me remind you Cadets this academy bears the name
来自罗马帝国将军格奈乌斯·多米提乌斯·科布罗
of the Roman General Gnaeus Domitius Corbulo,
因为他代表了荣誉、勇气和忠诚
because he represents honor, valor, allegiance.
科布罗将军被暴君尼禄
General Corbulo was to take his own life
下令自杀
in the name of the Empire.
科布罗没有犹豫，也从未怀疑
Corbulo did not hesitate nor question.
他忠实地履行了命令
He loyally obeyed,
在喊出「Axios」后倒在了自己的剑下
screaming Axios as he fell upon his own sword.
Axios...
"我…"
"I..."
"是…"
"am..."
"值得的…"
"worthy."
但是今天，我恐怕你们证明的
But I'm afraid, Cadets, today,
是完全相反的事实
you have proven to be anything but.
我们正在与叛军交战
We are at war with insurrectionists,
这些恐怖分子只想杀死我们所有人
terrorists who would like nothing more than to see all of us dead.
如果这是一场真正的战斗的话
Had this been a real firefight,
叛军早就把哈斯塔提小队彻底歼灭了
the rebels would have likely killed every member of Hastati Squad.
你们能够到这所学校来学习
Every single one of you at this academy was sent here
是因为你们的父母都是在联合国太空指挥部
because your parents are the upper echelon
工作的高层人员
of the United Nations Space Command,
你们就是未来的接班人
because all of you are its future,
我希望你们配得上对你们的期望
and I expect you to act like it.
明白了，长官！
Understood, sir!
那么，你们还在等什么？
Well, what are you waiting for?
带他们去跑步吧，奥瑞斯基！
Lead them on tour, Orenski!
Axios!
CADETS: Axios!
哈斯塔提，向右-转！
APRIL: Hastati, right face!
跑步-走！
Double time!
□ 每天清早，大概5点 □
APRIL: ? One early morning 'bout zero-five ?
CADETS: ? One early morning 'bout zero-five ?
□ 大地颤抖 □
APRIL: ? Ground will rumble ?
□ 闪电劈空 □
? With lightning in the sky ?
□ 大地颤抖 □
CADETS: ? Ground will rumble ?
□ 闪电劈空 □
? With lightning in the sky ?
(cadence continues, fades)
科布罗军事科学学院：环状星系IV
□ 地狱骑兵，地狱骑兵，你们去了哪里？ □
APRIL: ? Helljumper, Helljumper, where you been? ?
CADETS: ? Helljumper, Helljumper, where you been? ?
□ 地狱里走一遭又回来 □
APRIL: ? Feet first into hell and back again ?
CADETS: ? Feet first into hell and back again ?
□ 别为我哭泣，别为我流泪 □
APRIL: ? Don't cry for me, don't shed no tears ?
CADETS: ? Don't cry for me, don't shed no tears ?
(wheezing)
(cadets singing cadence indistinctly)
□ 地狱骑兵，地狱骑兵，你们去了哪里？ □
APRIL: ? Helljumper, Helljumper, where you been? ?
CADETS: ? Helljumper, Helljumper, where you been? ?
□ 做好准备，再赴地狱 □
APRIL: ? Been out on a drop, we'll jump again ?
CADETS: ? Been out on a drop, we'll jump again ?
(wheezing)
□ 一、二、三、四 □
? One, two, three, four ?
(cadets conversing indistinctly)
不，真的，我这正忙着呢
SULLY: No, seriously, I'm onto something here.
结果看起来乱七八糟的
The come are messed up,
但我正在解密一些大猛料
but I'm decoding something kick-ass.
我确定海军情报处把一些资料藏起来了 （ONI在Halo 3，Halo 3 ODST和Halo Reach均有出现）
ONI's hiding stuff from us, I'm positive.
他们有秘密
They've got secrets.
别老掉链子了，拉斯基！
Stop stepping on our dicks, Lasky!
嘿，冷静点儿，生姜头
Hey, ease up, gingerbread.
不，小苏，韦克斯是对的
JJ: Nah, Sully, Vickers is right.
因为你，我的战斗分数糟透了
My combat scores suck because of you.
别管他了，JJ，他心软了
DIMAH: Don't bother, JJ. He's gone soft.
他现在是叛军的同情者了
He's an Innie lover now.
迪玛，那条命令根本没有道理的
Dimah, that order didn't make any sense.
不用有道理，遵守就是了
Doesn't have to make sense, just follow it.
我只是想在这里坚持下来，明白？
I'm trying to survive here, okay?
你需要尊重指挥级别
You need to respect chain of command.
UNSC不是你的敌人，叛军们才是
The UNSC isn't the enemy, the looies are.
说的好像你相信似的
Spoken like a true believer.
是啊，这个么，至少现在我相信一些东西
Yeah, well, at least I believe in something these days.
学员托马斯·拉斯基
COMPUTER VOICE: Cadet Thomas Lasky,
请立即到麦哈非上校办公室报到
report to Colonel Mehaffey's office immediately.
(Speaking indistinctly)
(Tether whooshes past)
听着，我们还是按照原计划行动，明白？
WALTER: (on recording) No, we're sticking to my plan, okay?
听我的指挥
On my mark.
行不通的
THOMAS: (on recording) It won't work.
汤姆，就听他的吧
CHYLER: Tom, just do what he says.
这是我的命令
WALTER: They're my orders.
我不管
THOMAS: I don't care.
暂停
MEHAFFEY: Pause.
你不管？
You don't care?
你知道你的头盔是可以记录一切情况的吧？
You do realize your helmets transmit everything?
没有理由，长官！
No excuse, sir.
如果你继续拖你的小队的后腿
You continue pulling down your squad,
最终结果就是四面树敌
you're gonna end up with a lot of enemies.
明白，长官！
Yes, sir!
我曾在你母亲手下服役
I served under your mother.
我知道她是什么样的人
I know what she's like,
我相信你我都非常清楚这一点
and I sure as hell don't need to tell you
拉斯基上校是绝对不会让她的儿子
that Colonel Lasky's not gonna let a son of hers
没拿到毕业证书就离开学院的
leave this academy without a diploma.
我没法知道自己的母亲怎么想，长官
I wouldn't know what my mother thinks, sir.
我从未见过她
I never see her.
这是一场漫长的战争
It's been a long war.
你母亲掌握着很多人的命运
Your mother holds a lot of hands.
这个有人告诉我了，长官
So I'm told, sir.
你看，托马斯
You know, Thomas,
在这里我送走过很多毕业学员
I've seen a lot of Cadets come through here.
很多人像你一样承受了很大的压力和痛苦
Many have suffered like you.
虽然痛苦可能难以忘却
Pain like that cannot be forgotten,
但你可以学到如何去忍受它
but you can learn how to tolerate it.
我会尽力的，长官
I'll do my best, sir.
就这样吧
MEHAFFEY: That'll be all.
你起这些水泡有多久了？
DR. HUGHES: How long have you had those blisters?
断断续续有几周了，不过这些是昨天起的
THOMAS: Been on and off for a few weeks, but these are from yesterday.
还有其他症状么？
DR. HUGHES: Any other symptoms?
呼吸有点儿困难
It's getting hard to breathe.
哦，好吧，让我们继续观察
Okay, well, let's keep an eye on it.
生化冷冻舱训练是要你交点儿学费的
Cryo training can take its toll.
（警告：限制进入区域） （红字：冲向死亡）
(Tether whirring)
(Cadets conversing)
给我出去！
MAN: Get out of my room!
怎么了，伙计？
What the hell, man?
（叛军袭击民用航空港 数十人被杀）
埃里克，把你的脏手拿开，不然我就杀了你！
WOMAN: Eric, get your filthy hands off me or I will kill you!
嗨
Hey.
(gunfire)
(sounds of combat)
小苏，你真的不该看那些东西
DIMAH: You really shouldn't be looking at that stuff, Sully.
成功
Score.
来自火星新哈曼尼殖民地的最新消息
WOMAN: (on video feed): The latest from New Harmony, Mars,
一对叛军指挥官今天被逮捕
a pair of insurrectionist operatives were apprehended.
这个杂种！他偷了我的枕头！
MAN: What an asshole! He stole my pillow!
俊杰，你的学业表现非凡
(speaking Chinese dialect)
比我们预料的好
但是，第一节的成绩单，作战的部分不好
(speaking Chinese dialect)
嗨，小弟，这是来自杰里科7号殖民地的问候
Hey, little bro. Hello from Jericho 7.
现在是任务的第131天，我要给你看些东西
It's day 131 in deployment, so I got to show you something.
妈妈看到这个肯定会气晕过去的
Mom's gonna flip when she sees this,
但管她呢
but whatever.
这个还有些粗糙，不过因为我们下周
I'm still a little raw, but we got a big drop
要去空降叛军的一处要塞
on an Innie stronghold next week,
所以我想在行动之前把这个搞定
and I wanted to get it done before then.
不管怎样…
Anyways...
所以你还没上军事法庭么？
CHYLER: So you haven't been court-martialed yet then?
我不会道歉的
I'm not apologizing.
不，你会的
Yes, you are.
至少我相信某些事情？
At least I believe in something?
我确实相信一些事
I do believe in something.
- 是的，我也是 - 比如说？
- Yeah, so do I. - Like what?
我就是不相信那些导致无止境杀戮的愚蠢命令
Just not in stupid orders that lead to needless violence.
谈判已经不是一个选项了，汤姆
Negotiating isn't an option any more, Tom.
所以我们是在给孩子们洗脑
So we're brainwashing kids
然后送他们去消灭那些受够了苛捐杂税的农民们
and then sending them in to exterminate a bunch of overtaxed farmers.
农民？你以为他们都是那样的人么？
Farmers? That's who you think they are?
你真的不知道叛军们都是什么样的
You have no idea what the looies are like.
我很了解的
I have a pretty good idea.
那么，你就应该知道他们有多恨我们
Well, then you should know how much they hate us,
他们不把我们全都杀光是不会停手的
and that they're not going to stop fighting until we're all dead.
你能说都是他们的错么？
Can you blame them?
是，当然能
Yeah, I can.
很多事情都是他们的错
I blame them for a lot of things.
你也应该谴责他们
And you should, too.
呃，注意安全，完成任务
Uh, staying safe, doing my job.
我只是想提醒你，做好自己的任务
I just wanted to remind you to do your job.
哦，顺便说下
Oh, and by the way,
将的漂亮，哥们儿，又赢了
nice Checkmate, bro, yet again.
好吧，再来一盘，你先走
Okay, new game, your move.
坚持住
And hang in there.
我知道妈妈一直不在身边的感觉不好受
I know it's tough with Mom being gone all the time.
那种孤独的感觉
Being alone.
她爱你，我也爱你
She loves you. So do I.
想你了，兄弟
Miss you, buddy.
我也想你
Miss you, too.
熄灯时间到，宿舍门关闭
COMPUTER VOICE: Lights out, doors closing.
（…冲向黎明，从地球，为了地球，荣誉、勇气、忠诚、完美…）
(tapping)
(rumbling)
(alarm sounding)
快点儿，JJ，机器人要发火了！
WALTER: Come on, JJ! The Robot's gonna be pissed!
(Imitating alarm)
闭嘴，小苏！
JJ: Shut up, Sully!
搞定了！
(seal on door hisses)
I got it!
笨蛋，你T恤都穿反了
JJ: Shirt's on backwards, asshole.
快！快，快，快！
APRIL: Go! Go, go, go!
赶快到集合点！
Get there quick!
快，快跑！
Go, keep moving!
你那是跳芭蕾么？
Are you tippy-toeing?
醒醒，哈斯塔提，速度！
Wake up, Hastati, move it!
快点儿！别睡了！
Faster! Wake up!
布莱克将军起的有点儿早啊，你说呢？
Little early for General Black, don't you think?
怎么停下了？
Why are you stopping?
你是在等你的好妈妈
Are you waiting for your fancy mommy
来帮你穿衣服么？
to come and finish it for you?
你这就是慢动作！
That looks like slow motion to me!
别迷糊了，哈斯塔提！
Wake up, Hastati!
不喜欢早上4点被叫起来？
Don't like being up at 0400?
那明天就安排3点
Tomorrow it'll be 0300.
- 武器检查完毕！ - 武器检查完毕！
- Weapons check! - Weapons check!
奥伦，开灯
Orlen, lights.
学员？学员！
BLACK: Cadet? Cadet!
你已经死了，小子
You're already dead, son.
奥伦，席尔瓦学员的时间？
Orlen, Cadet Silva's time?
是51.07秒，艾普莉·奥瑞斯基学员
COMPUTER VOICE: 51.07 seconds, Cadet April Orenski.
今天还不够好，韦克斯学员
Not good enough today, Cadet Vickers.
我相信席尔瓦学员的成绩让学院的记录蒙羞
I believe Cadet Silva's time was just shy of the Academy record
记录保持者是凯德蒙·拉斯基
held by Cadmon Lasky.
那，才是一个真正的士兵
Now, that was a real soldier,
一个永不放弃的士兵
a soldier who did not give up.
明天你们小队将有本学期
Tomorrow you will engage
最后一场大型训练课
in the last major exercise of this term.
哈斯塔提小队在本学院的命运
Hastati Squad's future at this academy
就看你们的表现了
will depend on its performance.
(touchscreen screen beeps)
爸爸你好，收到你的留言了，谢谢
(speaking Chinese dialect)
今天在一次实战演练中我得到了最高分
(beeps)
(sounds of combat)
成功
你从哪儿找到这个的？
Score.
迪玛?
DIMAH: Where did you get this?
Dimah?
你会惹上大麻烦的
DIMAH: You could get in a lot of trouble.
你看，你不能把这件事告诉你妈妈，好么？
Now, you can't tell your mom about this, okay?
我什么都不会说的
I won't say anything.
通告：选频通信系统
COMPUTER VOICE: Advisory: select communications systems
将于4点开始维护
will be down for system maintenance at 0400.
Will be down for system maintenance at 0400.
韦克斯学员？
APRIL: Cadet Vickers?
是的，长官！
Yes, sir!
你应该清楚昨天我不得不和你们一起跑步
You realize you and Lasky are the reason
都是因为你和拉斯基的事
I had to run the tour yesterday with you newbs,
而且我们还要早上4点起来
and why we all had to get up at 0400.
明白，长官！
Yes, sir!
所以，你能想到，我现在很饿…
So, as you can imagine, I'm pretty hungry...
而且我很喜欢学院食堂的乳蛋饼
and I do love this academy's quiche.
干得好，艾普莉
MAN: Nice, April.
长官
Sir.
所以，你们两个，把食物交上来
So hand them over, both of you.
有这样显赫的家世
With such a renowned pedigree,
我自然期望你能够做一个更棒的士兵，拉斯基
I sure expected you to be a better soldier, Lasky.
长官
Sir.
解散
You're dismissed.
你妈妈一定很不容易
Must be tough on your mom
知道她的亲生儿子再也回不了家了
knowing her real son's never coming home.
哇！拉斯基和韦克斯！
SULLY: Whoa! Lasky and Vickers!
拉斯基！
Lasky!
军官到！
Officer on deck!
到外面来
Outside.
你到底是怎么回事？
MEHAFFEY: What the hell is wrong with you?
- 回答我 - 没什么事，长官！
- Answer me. - Nothing, sir!
好吧，也许你还有点儿希望
Well, maybe there's hope for you yet.
长官？
Sir?
托马斯，你体内流着一个士兵的血
There's a soldier inside of you, Thomas.
我能看得出，大家都看得出
I can see it. Everyone can see it.
你自己也要看得出！
You need to see it!
我知道你哥哥也是这样的
I know your brother did.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
现在去把你自己洗干净，准备上课
Now go get yourself cleaned up before class.
Axios!
(touchscreen beeps)
嗨，兄弟
Hey, bro.
从阿卡迪亚向你问好，阿卡迪亚的丛林
Hello from Arcadia, the jungles of Arcadia.
我跟你说点儿什么呢？
So what can I tell you?
跟他说说你的新外号！
MAN: (on video) Tell him how you got your new nickname!
- 不行 - 那我告诉他！
- No. - I'll tell him!
得了吧，我发誓！我会告诉他的，我跟他说
Come on, I swear! I'll tell him. I'll tell him.
好吧，你会喜欢这个的
All right, you're especially gonna love this.
几周前我们跳伞进入一片热带雨林
So we make a drop into the rainforest a couple weeks ago.
我们看见一条河，我和小伙子们
We see this river, me and the boys,
决定喝一口水
we decide to take a dip.
里奇警告我们说不要喝河水
Rich warns us all not to drink the water.
是的，我说了
RICH: Yeah, I did.
显然晚了，我头一件事就是喝了个饱
Of course, the first thing I do is to get a mouthful.
结果我差点儿把我的贴身作战服都毁了
I almost ruined my body suit a couple times,
所以，现在他们叫我，呃，火山
so now they call me, uh, Volcano.
哈哈！火山！
MAN: Ha ha! Volcano!
火山！火山！
(group chanting) Volcano! Volcano!
Volcano! Volcano!
钳形攻势…
MEHAFFEY: The Pincer Movement...
这种战术最早出现于地球上的第二次布匿战争
the strategy used in Earth's Second Punic War
迦太基对抗罗马的坎尼会战
against the Roman Republic at the Battle of Cannae.
奥伦，开始
Orlen, begin.
课程开始
COMPUTER VOICE: Lesson beginning.
红色表示罗马军队
MEHAFFEY: Red represents the Roman's troops,
蓝色是汉尼拔的军队
blue Hannibal's.
汉尼拔把他的长矛手和投石兵放在前面
Hannibal placed his spearmen and slingers at the front.
后面是他的剑士，侧翼是骑兵
Behind them, his swordsmen flanked by cavalry.
当罗马人进攻的时候
When the Romans attacked,
汉尼拔的剑士们先是向后撤退
Hannibal's swordsmen retreated.
在罗马人看来，对方是因为害怕自己的人数优势而逃走
To the Romans, that seemed to be due to their force,
但实际上，是汉尼拔下令撤退的
but in reality, Hannibal had ordered the retreat.
当罗马人继续向前追击剑士的时候
As the Romans continued to drive the swordsmen back,
汉尼拔的骑兵已经包抄到了罗马军队的后面
Hannibal's cavalry galloped in from behind.
当两个钳合在一起的时候
Once the attacking pincers connected,
罗马人就被彻底包围了
the Romans were completely surrounded.
这是真实的战术？
This is an actual strategy?
看起来很简单啊
It does seem a little basic.
罗马人比汉尼拔的军队要多出至少10000人
The Romans outnumbered Hannibal's troops by over 10,000 strong,
但是，他们却被击败了
and yet, they were defeated.
为什么？
Why?
傲慢
Hubris.
永远不要低估你的对手
Never underestimate your opponents.
永远不要低估他们为了胜利会付出什么代价
Never underestimate what they'll sacrifice for victory.
有什么问题么？
Questions?
有，我们怎么用这个战术呢？
Yeah, how do we apply this?
是啊，我们也没有马
Yeah, we don't have horses.
对，我们没有马，但我们有什么类似的？
MEHAFFEY: True, we don't, but what do we have instead?
地狱伞兵
CHYLER: ODSTs.
对极了，他们可以出现在敌人战线后方
Exactly. They drop behind enemy lines,
从战场后方或者中间攻击敌人
attack from the rear, neutralize.
或者战死沙场
THOMAS: Or die trying.
这是一个和战争本身一样古老的问题
MEHAFFEY: There's a question as old as war itself.
如果有人要杀死你
If someone is trying to kill you,
你难道不是要起来反抗，先杀死对方么？
are you not to rise against him and kill him first?
她说的每个字你都记下来了
THOMAS: You were hanging on her every word.
为什么不呢？
CHYLER: Why Wouldn't I?
我只是听到了一场无尽战争的隆隆战鼓声
THOMAS: I just hear the drumbeat of endless war,
说这些我也不能变成叛军的同情者
and that doesn't make me an Innie lover.
告诉我哪里错了
Tell me how wrong I am.
你看，你想要人们做出改变？
Look, you want people to change?
你想要结束这场战争？
You want this war to end?
当然
Of course.
那么你就需要有人来跟随你
Then you're gonna need people to follow you.
明天哈斯塔提小队会努力不再一次被钉在耻辱柱上！
Tomorrow Hastati Squad will try not to embarrass itself yet again!
你们是一个团队！
You are a unit!
你们的性命掌握在战友手中！
Your lives are in each other's hands!
今天早上的获胜者，席尔瓦学员，了解这一点
This morning's victor, Cadet Silva, knows this,
因为她的父母做出了最大的牺牲
because her parents gave the ultimate sacrifice
最终倒在了战场上
and died on the battlefield.
让我们在明天的训练课中获胜吧
Let success in tomorrow's exercise
不止是为了自己的荣誉
be not just for our honor,
也是为了那些牺牲自己让你们来这受训的人！
but for those who have fallen so you can be here!
所有学员请注意
COMPUTER VOICE: All Cadets, please be advised,
今晚新的宵禁时间是21点
new mandatory curfew tonight at 2100.
(woman speaking indistinctly on radio)
威胁等级：红色
Threat level Red.
（我们一同崛起）
(tapping)
(Chyler tapping)
本学期最终战斗训练课
COMPUTER VOICE: Final combat exercise of this term.
哈斯塔提对祖玛
Hastati versus Zuma.
Aah!
快，伙计！快走！
Come on, men! Let's go!
学员们，请准备注射生化冷冻剂
COMPUTER VOICE: Cadets, prepare for cryo injections.
向前-看！
APRIL: Attention!
今天的任务是夺旗
Today's mission is to capture the flag.
我希望结果能比上次好
I expect a better outcome than last time.
要求发言，长官！
Permission to speak, sir!
允许发言
Speak.
我要求带队，长官
I'd like to take point, sir.
好的，拉斯基，让我们看看真正的你
Okay, Lasky, let's see if you still got it in you.
但为了你好，你最好希望
But for your sake, you better hope
自己能够弄出什么魔法来
you can pull some magic out of your ass,
不然今年剩下的时间你就一直跑步吧
or you'll be running tour for the rest of the year.
明白，长官
Understood, sir.
(gas hissing)
(coughing)
哈斯塔提小队，1分钟到会合点
Hastati Squad, one minute to RV point.
现在对时，3，2，1，计时！
On my mark: three, two, one, mark!
上前！
DIMAH: Pick it up!
- 掩护！ - 移动！
- Cover! - Moving!
- 移动！ - 会合点已经在视野中！
- Moving! - RV point in sight!
没有祖玛小队的迹象
WALTER: No sign of Zuma!
我们走！快！快！
SULLY: Let's go! Move! Move!
继续走！
WALTER: Keep moving!
祖玛就在那边！小心！
Zuma's out here! Watch your backs!
- 移动！ - 移动！
- Moving! - Moving!
- 到达会合点 - 到达
- At RV point. - Here.
就到！
WALTER: Arriving!
人数相同
Equal numbers.
均势地形
THOMAS: Deadlocked terrain.
你的计划是？
What's your plan?
我们等着
We're waiting.
(Chyler sighs)
(Insects buzzing)
我们就这么等着？
Why are we just sitting here?
如果人数相同的话，我们就该去跟他们拼
If we have equal numbers, we should just fight it out.
别，要有耐心
(coughs) Yeah, just be patient.
气都喘不匀
WALTER: Wheezing freak.
(Beeping)
好了，他们移动了
Okay, they're moving.
摘掉你们的头盔
Take off your helmets.
什么？
What?
这是什么牌，拉斯基
That's pretty wildcard, Lasky.
我们这是盲打啊
We'll be flying blind.
相信我
Trust me.
注意，注意
ZUMA SQUAD LEADER: Eyes up. Eyes up.
好，从侧面包抄他们
All right, flank 'em.
他们在那里，所有人都在一处
That's them. They're all together.
找到他们了！
WOMAN: Found 'em!
哈？
MAN: Huh?
(gunfire) (screams)
(gunfire)
行动！
(groaning)
Now!
凯勒，掩护！
(coughing)
THOMAS: Chyler, cover!
(gunshot) - Aah!
Aah!
(panting)
拉斯基？
SULLY: (muffled) Lasky?
(light clicks)
(coughs)
发生了什么事？
What happened?
你在训练课过程中晕过去了
You passed out during the training exercise.
我的胸口感觉好像要着火了
My chest feels like it's on fire.
你起的水泡和呼吸困难这些症状
DR. HUGHES: Turns out the cryo blisters and your difficulty breathing
都是由于你对生化冷冻抗体过敏导致的
are an allergic reaction to the cytoprethaline.
这种药物是在生化冷冻休眠过程中
It's a drug we inject to keep ice crystals
防止细胞体结冰用的
from forming in your cells during cryo sleep.
发病率大概是50000之一
It occurs in about one in every 50,000 or so.
所以，每次我从生化冷冻休眠中醒来，我都不能呼吸
So I won't be able to breathe every time I wake up from cryo sleep.
你的过敏源浓度结果还没出来
The intensity of your allergy is still undetermined.
几个小时之内就会有确定结果
I'll know more in a few hours.
我希望你能够放松心情，今天剩下的时间都好好休息
I want you to take it real easy the rest of the day today.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
(Sighs)
(Sounds of distant combat)
你好，兄弟
Hey, bro.
我在安德西亚，再有一次任务就回家了
I'm on Andesia. It's a jump away from home.
这是第，嗯…
It's day, uh...
496天
496.
很抱歉昨天我没上线
I'm sorry I didn't com yesterday.
没法上来，因为我们一场战斗打了7个小时
Couldn't. We got pinned in a firefight for seven hours.
嗯，我想我大概能消灭了一打儿叛军吧
Uh, I must have killed a dozen looies, though.
妈妈会很开心的
Mom would be proud.
我在这边做的很好
I'm doing real good work here.
我们干的不错
We're doing a good thing.
里奇没能挺过来
Rich didn't make it.
就是咱们家乡的那个里奇
You remember Rich from back home.
他就在我身边，然后…
He was right there next to me and then...
他没能熬过来
he wasn't.
一颗榴弹把他炸向4个不同的方向
A pineapple sent him flying in four different directions.
为了里奇，我把头发都剃了
I had to shave it all off for Rich.
他说这样可以让我看起来更像个硬汉
He said it'd make me look tougher.
不管怎样，呃…
Anyways, uh...
我要走了，兄弟
I got to go, bro.
我等不及要回家了
I can't wait to get home.
咱们到时候见，凯德蒙通话完毕
I'll see you. Cadmon out.
(touchscreen beeps)
你在做什么呢？
What are you doing?
你何必这样折磨自己呢？
Why do you torment yourself with these?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我本该更好的
CHYLER: Whoa!
休医生怎么说的？
THOMAS: I've been better.
What did Dr. Hughes say?
他说没事
That it's nothing.
真的？
Really?
今天我们赢了
You know, we won today.
你的战术奏效了
Your strategy worked.
我只是当了回队长罢了
That's just me being a leader.
拉斯基，醒醒
SULLY: (on video screen) Lasky, wake up.
噢，嘿，凯勒
Oh, hey, Chyler.
噢，什么事，小苏？
Oh. What's up, Sully?
来我这儿，给你们看样东西
SULLY: Get in here. You guys gotta see this.
你看上去糟透了
WALTER: You look like crap.
敬请观赏我拼凑出来的绝密非官方情报吧
SULLY: So feast your eyes on Grade-A
classified nonlisted intelligence vids I pieced together.
拼这东西太累人了，但很值啊
Super pain in the ass to do, but so worth it.
(gunfire, shouting)
这比最高机密还机密啊
DIMAH: This is beyond top secret.
我从没看到过如此复杂的加密影像
SULLY: I've never seen something encrypted so hard,
但我还是破解了
but I cracked it.
太疯狂了，不是么？
JJ: Wow.
是啊
SULLY: It's crazy, huh?
目标已锁定
JJ: Yeah.
MAN (on video): Target located.
等下，等下，马上就是最精彩的部分了
SULLY: Wait, wait, wait. Now here comes the best part.
看这里，看他的手
Wait, watch this. Watch his hand.
目标已捕获
MAN: Target acquired!
不，别！他们来了！他们来了！
No, no! They're coming! They're coming!
那家伙比海军陆战队员还高2英尺
JJ: That thing is like two feet taller than the marine.
太疯狂了
DIMAH: Pretty crazy, huh?
现在看这儿
SULLY: Now check this out.
(gunfire)
小队，遭遇不明敌军，撤退
MAN: Squad, encountered unknown hostiles. Going back.
噢，怎么可能！
(Man screams)
JJ: Oh, no way!
你们觉得他们在逃避谁？
SULLY: Now, who do you think they're running from?
他们联手攻击了么？
Are they fighting together?
好了，现在到整段的高潮了
SULLY: Okay, now here comes the best part.
看，看这儿
Wait, watch... watch this.
那家伙是什么？
JJ: VVhoa! WALTER: What is that thing?
你们都看到了吗？
SULLY: Do you get this? Are you seeing all this?
现在时间18点整
COMPUTER VOICE: It is now 1800.
所有学员去食堂报到
All Cadets report to the Mess Hall.
你觉得那家伙是什么？
SULLY: What do you think that thing was?
肯定不是地狱伞兵
JJ: Definitely not an ODST.
那他会是什么？
SULLY: Then what could it be?
可能是某种改良版地狱伞兵护甲
WALTER: Maybe some upgraded ODST armament.
拜托，你没瞧见他有多巨大？
JJ: Come on, did you not see the size of that thing?
绝不会是地狱伞兵
That's not ODST.
(imitating gunfire)
各位，你们都没抓住要点
Guys, look, you're missing the point.
重点是我方士兵和叛军并肩作战
What matters is that our soldiers
were fighting alongside the insurrectionists.
我们为何要保护敌军？
Why would we protect the enemy?
拉斯基学员？
Cadet Lasky?
麦哈非上校要见你
Colonel Mehaffey would like to see you.
你好些了么？
MEHAFFEY: How are you feeling?
我胸还是很痛，长官
My chest burns, sir, quite a bit.
这是给你的
This is for you.
看起来你要做出个决定，托马斯
Seems like you have a choice to make, Thomas.
我不明白，长官
I don't understand, sir.
看上去休医生的诊断发现你对西蒲赛林的
It appears Dr. Hughes' test has revealed
that the level of your allergy to cytoprethaline
过敏程度足以批准你因病退伍
is serious enough to warrant a medical discharge.
如果你觉得你不再适合服役
If you feel that you are unfit for service,
你只要在这儿签字并带到太空电梯去
all you need to do is sign the release and bring it to the Tether.
我什么时候会走？
When would I leave?
明天
MEHAFFEY: Tomorrow.
明天？
Tomorrow?
你知道的，托马斯
You know, Thomas,
你留下的将会是你的回忆和决定
your memories and choices are all you'll have left.
游戏最后，将和卒都会放会棋盒 （不管是伟人还是凡人，死后都会去同样的地方）
At the end of the game,
the king and the pawn go into the same box.
你必须决定你愿意牺牲什么
You have to decide what you're willing to sacrifice.
Axios
MEHAFFEY: Axios.
Axios.
(Cadets conversing indistinctly)
托马斯，我要告诉你一件无比沉痛的事
(touchscreen beeps)
Thomas, it is with a heavy heart that I must inform you
今天你哥哥凯德蒙在安德西亚被叛军杀了
that today your brother, Cadmon, was shot down
by insurrectionist forces on Andesia.
他的小队成员都被杀了
All of his squad perished.
他们死时应该很快，毫无痛苦
I've been told it was a quick and painless death.
没有遗骸留下
There are no remains to bury.
鉴于此，我决定你
With this in mind, I have decided that you
不应该离开科布罗学院参加葬礼…
shall not leave Corbulo to attend services...
(Colonel Lasky's voice fades)
(Inaudible)
拉斯基上校通话完毕
Colonel Lasky out.
拉斯基？
SULLY: Lasky?
拉斯基，挪开，我给你看样东西
Lasky, move over. I gotta show you something.
我不是很方便，小苏
Now's not a good time, Sully, okay?
这真的很重要
No, it's important.
这他妈的是啥？
SULLY: Now what the hell is that?
Hmm?
哇！怎么回事？
Whoa! Whoa! What...?
离线了
It's offline.
我搞砸了，是海军情报处干的
I'm screwed, man. It's ONI.
他们肯定标记了这些影片
They must have flagged those come.
我要去问问迪玛
I got to talk to Dimah.
迪玛？你跟你妈说过那事？
Dimah? Did you tell your mom?
凯勒？
Chyler?
(crickets chirping)
嘿
THOMAS: Hey.
我一直都挺想坐坐你这个位子
CHYLER: I thought I'd give your spot a try.
那段影片根本说不通
That com didn't make any sense.
我的理解一直是敌人都是可憎的
Hating the looies is all I've ever known.
你跟麦哈非上校说过吗？
Did you tell Mehaffey about it?
没
No.
没有
那是什么？
What's that?
我显然是对战争过敏
Apparently, I'm allergic to war.
什么意思？
What does this mean?
你要离开这儿？
You're leaving?
嗯，如果我签字的话明天就走
Yeah, tomorrow, if I sign it.
你打算签么？
Are you going to?
我不知道
I don't know.
凯勒…
Chyler...
没关系的
It's okay.
我知道你不想待在这儿
I know you don't want to be here.
我只是想也许…
I just thought that maybe...
我会想念你的
I'll miss you.
(alarm siren sounds)
怎么回事？
What is that?
所有学员去太空电梯处报到
COMPUTER VOICE: All Cadets report to the Tether.
我不知道
I don't know.
全校疏散
COMPUTER VOICE: Campus-wide evacuation.
去太空电梯那儿，快！
To the Tether, now!
这不是演习！
This is not a drill!
快！抓紧！
Let's go, let's go, let's go! Come on!
快走！
WOMAN: Okay, let's go!
全校疏散
COMPUTER VOICE: Full campus evacuation.
全校…
Campus-wide...
(Cadets shouting)
快走，学员们！
MAN: Move it, Cadets!
Now, now! Move it, Cadets!
快！快走！
Go! Move, move!
赶紧去你的小队那里！
MEHAFFEY: Go to your squads, now!
快！快走！
MAN: Let's go! Move! Move!
动起来，学员们！
SECOND MAN: Keep moving, Cadets!
凯勒、拉斯基，其他队员都在电梯那了，快走吧
Chyler, Lasky, the rest of the squad's already at the Tether. Let's go.
保持冷静
COMPUTER VOICE: Remain calm.
快走！
MAN: Move! Move!
哈斯塔提小队！这里！
Hastati! This way!
快点！来这里！
Hurry up! Right here! Right here!
拉斯基、陈，快！
Lasky, Chen, let's go!
好吧，凑紧了，保持队形
Okay, hold tight, stay in line.
怎么回事？叛军来了？
What is this? insurrectionists?
我不知道
I have no idea.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
我们只须排好队，乘上太空电梯，好吗？
We're just lining up. We're gonna get onto the Tether, okay?
(Rumbling, objects whistling as they fall)
出发！
(Crash)
Go! Let's go!
这是…
What the...
为什么地狱伞兵来这了？
Why are ODSTs dropping here?
我不知道
JJ: I don't know.
因为我们受到攻击
Because we're under attack.
保持冷静
COMPUTER VOICE: Remain calm.
维持秩序
Maintain order.
(Explosions, objects whistling)
这不好
This is not good.
地狱伞兵一出现就没好事
ODSTs dropping is never good.
我不管了
Screw this.
我能带大家快速上电梯
I can get us on this wagon.
- 不，别，我们要待在这 - 对
- No, no, no, we will hold our position. - Yeah.
各位，来啊
Guys, come on.
不，切科娃，这是命令
APRIL: No, Tchakova, that is a direct order.
随你们便
Suit yourself.
- 迪玛！ - 迪玛！
- Dimah! - Dimah!
赶紧归队！
Get back in line right now!
迪玛！
JJ: Dimah!
回你的小队去，学员
Return to your squad, Cadet.
我要乘上这电梯
I'm getting on this wagon.
满了，等下一部
It's full. Wait for the next one.
我妈是舰队指挥部部长
My mother is Secretary of FleetCom.
你看着办吧，士兵
Your choice, marine.
去吧
Go.
电梯满了！别让她上来！
MAN: Wagon full! Send her off!
我们等太久了，艾普莉
This is taking too long, April.
我们也该像迪玛那样赶紧离开这儿
Maybe we should bum-rush like Dimah.
不，我们没事的
No, no, no, no. We'll be fine.
(ships rumbling)
这是什么玩意儿？
What the hell are those things?
快逃！
Go!
(Debris falling, screams)
(Cadets shouting)
啊！
Aah!
(explosion)
(Footsteps, breathing)
托马斯？
(Muffled) Tom?
(Muffled explosions)
别动！
Steady!
(creature lands with a thud)
(distant gunfire)
(speaking alien language)
噢老天，那是什么？
CHYLER: Oh, my God, what is that?
(Heavy footsteps thudding)
(speaking alien language)
托马斯，快走！
CHYLER: Tom, come on! Come on!
那是什么？
THOMAS: What was that?
我不知道
CHYLER: I don't know.
那是什么？！
APRIL: What was that?!
(woman screaming, glass shatters)
快走！
APRIL: Come on, come on!
快逃！
Run! Run! Go!
(Objects thud)
飞弹！
(gunfire)
MAN: Incoming!
- 快跑！ - 快！
- Move it! - Come on!
快跑！
Come on!
小心！
Watch out!
在那儿！
Up there!
啊！
Aah!
凯勒！哈斯塔提小队！
Chyler! Hastati!
去门那儿！快！
Get to the door! Go!
麦哈非上校
Colonel Mehaffey.
快去！
Go, go, go, go!
啊！
Aah!
(speaking alien language)
托马斯！快来！
Tom! Come on! Let's go!
撤退！
MAN: Fall back!
(all shouting)
- 快走！ - 快！
- Let's go! - Come on!
去宿舍！
SULLY: To the dorms!
怎么回事？
JJ: What's happening?
门锁了！
WALTER: The doors are locked!
来这里，进拉斯基的房间
Over here, in Lasky's room.
快来！
APRIL: Come on! Come on, come on!
噢老天！
Oh, my God!
迪玛死了！
Dimah, she's dead!
麦哈非上校也是
Colonel Mehaffey.
我们不能束手待毙！
We will be too if we don't do something!
通讯坏了
Corns are offline.
这是场新战争
THOMAS: It's a whole new war.
(woman screaming)
听起来很近了！
That sounded close!
(Heavy footsteps)
(creature speaking alien language)
它还能隐形
It's invisible.
什么会隐形？
What the hell's invisible?
有一个怪物进来了，它还会隐形
One of the things is inside, and it is invisible.
(Heavy footsteps thudding)
(Crash)
(creature growling)
(Heavy footsteps)
(Crash)
(Man screaming)
它来了，我们要离开这儿！
It's coming. We got to get out of here!
不，我们要留在这儿！
No, no, no, screw that! We stay here!
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we gonna go?
不，我们要去训练室
No, no, no, we're gonna go to the training room.
我们要武装起来，我们要搞到些武器
We're gonna get gacked up, we're gonna get some weapons.
我领队
I'll take point.
好的，排队！
APRIL: Come on, come on, line up!
好了，告诉我们何时冲出去
All right, tell us when.
告诉我们何时冲出去，好吗？
Tell us when, all right?
(Crash)
该死
Sheez.
(Silence)
就现在！
(crash) - Now!
(creature growling)
快跑，快！
APRIL: Go! Go, go, go, go, go!
快！怎么…
Go, hurry! What...
各位？
THOMAS: Guys?
你怎么停了，JJ？
(creature growls)
SULLY: Why'd you stop, JJ?
JJ！
JJ!
噢老天！快跑！
WALTER: Oh, my God! Go, go, go, go!
快！
Go! Go!
拉斯基，发送求救信号！
APRIL: Lasky, send the distress beacon!
凯勒，帮我拿这些武器！
Chyler, help me get the weapons!
快啊！
CHYLER: Let's go!
- 我的密码无效！ - 再试下！
- My code isn't working! - Try again!
拉斯基，关门！
Lasky, door!
我在关！
Yeah, I'm trying!
艾普莉，快点！
CHYLER: April, come on!
没用！
APRIL: I'm trying.
CHYLER: It's not working!
求救！求救！
THOMAS: Mayday, Mayday, Mayday!
我是托马斯·拉斯基学员！
This is Cadet Thomas Lasky!
重复，求救！求救！
I repeat, Mayday, Mayday!
科布罗学院发生交战
There's been an attack on Corbulo Academy,
很多人伤亡
excessive casualties.
重复，很多人伤亡！
I repeat, excessive casualties!
我没有权限取得实弹
I don't have access to the live rounds.
我觉得信号机也坏了
I think the beacon's down as well.
我们死定了
We're dead.
好吧，想想
Okay. All right, think, think.
仔细想想
Think, think, think.
我们不能待在这儿，艾普莉
We can't stay in here, April.
我们也不能出去
We can't go out there.
(Thud, Walter grunts)
Unh!
加油，韦克斯！用力！
用力，韦克斯！
Come on Vickers! Harder!
- Unh! - Harder, Vickers!
(Loud thud outside)
(thud)
快躲起来
Hide.
(thud)
(creature growling)
(creature speaking alien language)
(thud)
(Heavy footsteps)
(crash)
嘘
THOMAS: Shh.
(Heavy footsteps approaching)
(creature exhales)
(scrape)
(creature growls)
(Heavy footsteps withdrawing)
(distant thud)
好，走
(whispering) Okay, go.
拉斯基，去门那
SULLY: Lasky, go for the door.
我们不能抛下韦克斯
THOMAS: We can't leave Vickers.
它在哪儿？
Where is it?
(thud)
就在那儿
He's right there.
(Heavy footsteps thudding)
(creature growling)
(Radio crackles, creature speaking alien language)
(speaking alien language)
嘿！大伙儿快跑！
Hey! Guys, run!
啊！
Aah!
韦克斯！
SULLY: Vickers!
(speaking alien language)
(Growls)
(weapon buzzing)
(laughing, knife strike)
(groaning)
我们的时间不多了
MAN'S VOICE: We don't have much time.
我们走
Let's go.
凯莉，通知指挥部我这里有4名幸存者
CHIEF: Kelly, inform Command I have four survivors.
带你的小队北上
Take your team north.
在阿尔法撤离点乘鹈鹕号撤离
Rendezvous at Evac Alpha for Pelican extraction.
我们到那里汇合
We'll meet you there.
士官长完毕
Chief out.
你怎么找到我们的？
How did you find us?
求救信号
CHIEF: The distress beacon.
你为什么来救我们？
SULLY: Why did you come for us?
你们是仅存的幸存者了
CHIEF: You're the only survivors.
整所学院的？
In the school?
整个星球
On the planet.
我们有15分钟到达撤离点
We've got 15 minutes to get to the evac point.
武装起来
Armor up.
武器…锁起来了
SULLY: It's... it's locked.
(Distant crash)
保持安静
Stay quiet.
不管外面什么有动静都别离开
Do not leave no matter what you hear outside.
等下，你是谁？
THOMAS: Wait. Who are you?
叫我士官长
Call me Master Chief.
噢老天
SULLY: Oh, God.
我就知道那些海军情报处的影片是坏消息
I knew those ONI vids were bad news.
现在就我们几个活着了，而且…
Now we're the only ones alive, and...
小苏，别说话！
CHYLER: Sully, shh!
到底怎么回事？
SULLY: What the hell is going on?
我们现在都跟着一个大机器人
We're all following a giant robot.
天晓得他还会不会回来？
Who knows if he's even coming back?
他会回来的
He's gonna come back.
我相信他
I believe him.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我不知道
I don't know.
坚持住，我们会没事的
Hang on. We'll be all right.
嘿，你会没事的
Hey, hey, you're gonna be fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
(explosion outside)
(thud)
(Heavy footsteps thudding)
这里谁射得最准？
Who's the best shot here?
你吧
You probably.
是凯勒
Chyler is.
我还行
I'm good.
我也是
I am, too.
拉斯基学员，你会驾驶疣猪号吗？
Cadet Lasky, can you drive a Warthog?
呃…
Uh...
嗯，可以吧
Yeah, sure.
好，我们就向那里前进
Good. That's where we're headed.
射手站两边
Shooters on the left and right.
司机在当中
Driver in the center.
跟紧我
Stay close to me.
这样你们就能活下来
It's your best chance of survival.
(explosion)
小苏，跟上
THOMAS: (whispering) Sully, keep up.
小苏，快
APRIL: Sully, come on.
他们都去哪儿了？
SULLY: (stammering) Where'd they all go?
啊！
Aah!
(weapon fires)
- 头低下！ - 啊！
- Get down! - Aah!
去疣猪号，我来吸引火力
Get to the Hog. I'll draw their fire.
他去哪了？
CHYLER: Where'd he go?
士官长！
Chief!
掩护我！
Cover me!
拉斯基，快去！
Lasky, go!
- 你没事吧？ - 小苏我看着
- You okay? - I've got Sully.
去！
Go!
我去了！掩护我！
Moving! Cover me!
啊！
Aah!
头低着前进！
CHYLER: Stay low! Stay low!
(grunting)
凯勒，我没子弹了！
(clicking)
Chyler, I'm out!
把小苏给我！
Give me Sully!
我抓住你了
(Sully groans) - I got you.
啊！启动啊！
Ah! Come on!
(Power shuts down)
(clicking)
(gunshot)
(creature screams)
(frustrated grunt)
启动啊！
Come on!
(engine starts)
(Multiple gunshots)
艾普莉，快走
CHYLER: April, go!
加油，小苏！
APRIL: Come on, Sully!
快走！
Go!
快，凯勒！
APRIL: Come on, Chyler!
(engine revving)
快开！
Drive!
啊！
Aah!
拉斯基！
(tires screeching)
(Groans) APRIL: - Lasky!
这比看起来难开多了！
It's harder than it looks!
坚持住，小苏！
(Sully screaming) - Hang in there, Sully!
对不起！
THOMAS: Sorry!
你开的不错！开稳点就行！
You're doing fine! Just keep it steady!
朝右转，学员
Bear right, Cadet.
前方就是入口
There's an access directly ahead.
(whoosh)
开快点，学员
Faster, Cadet.
距鹈鹕号抵达还有4分钟
Four minutes to the Pelican.
我们必须离开这颗星球
We have to get off the planet.
啊！
Aah!
警告！即将撞击，系紧安全带！
(alarm beeping)
(creature screams)
精确点射！
CHIEF: Controlled bursts!
不要扫射！
Don't spray and pray.
学员，2点钟方向！
Cadet, two o'clock!
(creature screams)
凯勒，掩护我！
THOMAS: Chyler, cover!
掩护中！
CHYLER: Covering!
(creatures groan)
凯莉，追踪我们的方位
CHIEF: Kelly, track our position for evac.
我想我们安全了
I think we're clear.
(alarm beeping)
干的好
Nice job.
(Growls)
大家都没事吧？
(Sully groans) CHYLER: - Is everyone okay?
(engine won't start)
递给我生化泡沫，你去操纵机枪
Hand me the bio foam and man the gun.
启动啊！
THOMAS: Come on!
Come on!
啊，启动啊！
(engine won't start) - Ah, come on!
这能帮你走路
This'll help you walk.
该死
Gah.
我们都快到了
We're almost there.
托马斯？
Tom?
启动啊
Come on.
托马斯？
Tom?
托马斯
Tom.
士官长！士官长！
- Chief! Chief! (Chyler screams)
凯勒也被击中了！
Chyler's been hit!
啊！
CHYLER: Aah!
我没有生化泡沫了
CHIEF: I'm out of bio foam.
我们必须现在就把她送上鹈鹕号
We have to get her to the Pelican now.
(distant gunfire, creatures shouting)
它们在撤退
They're retreating.
它们为何这么做？
Why would they do that now?
我们被狩猎了
We're being hunted.
往北前进
Keep moving north.
你会看到我的小队的
You'll see my team.
尽全力跑过去，不管看到什么也别停下，包括我
Run as fast as you can and don't stop for anything, including me.
(explosion) (groans)
- 你能走么？ - 我试试
- Can you walk? - I'll try.
继续呼吸就好
Just keep breathing.
坚持住，好吗？坚持住
Just hang in there, okay? Hang in there.
快啊！
SULLY: Come on!
(Chyler groans)
我们必须带她去那里
APRIL: We gotta get her somewhere.
去隐棚
To the blind.
我们回去
Let's go back.
噢老天
THOMAS: Oh, my God.
(creature growls)
大家出发！
Guys, go!
快走！
THOMAS: Go! Go!
小苏，你还跟着我们么？
THOMAS: Sully, you with us?
嗯
SULLY: Yeah.
(Chyler groans)
坚持住，凯勒！
APRIL: Hang in there, Chyler!
(coughing)
我们会带你离开这儿的，知道吗？
We're gonna get you out of here, okay?
艾普莉？这是眩晕弹
SULLY: April? Stun rounds.
这会麻醉你的伤口，明白吗？
This will numb the pain, okay?
坚持住，凯勒
THOMAS: Hang in there, Chyler.
坚持住，凯勒，坚持住
Hang in there, Chyler. Come on, hang in there.
没事的，托马斯
It's okay, Tom.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别这样说
No, please.
凯勒
(Crying) Chyler.
(Heavy footsteps approaching)
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我需要你的弹药，学员
I need your ammo, Cadets.
把那猎人干倒用光了我的弹药
It took everything I had to bring that thing down.
我们也没有了
SULLY: We don't have any.
只有眩晕弹了，长官
Just stun rounds, sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
各位？
(rumbling) - Guys?
又来一只，快走！
There's another one. Move now!
你必须离开她，托马斯
You have to leave her, Tom.
对不起
I'm sorry.
拉斯基，快跟上！
SULLY: Lasky, come on!
拉斯基，快啊！
APRIL: Lasky, come on, come on!
(Explosions)
(gunfire)
(creature growls)
(groaning)
那里！
CHIEF: There!
凯莉，再给我点时间
CHIEF: Kelly, need more time.
目前没法到达会合点
Cannot make it to the rendezvous.
你让鹈鹕号停在那儿
You have to hold the Pelican.
我不会丢下他们！
I won't leave them!
士官长完毕
Chief out.
我来跟它交手
CHIEF: I'll engage.
你们尽力跑去鹈鹕号
Get to the Pelican as fast as you can.
不，长官！
No, sir!
我来当诱饵
I'll be the decoy.
拉斯基，别！
Lasky, no!
你绕到它后面去
You swing in from behind.
学员
Cadet.
拉斯基！
Lasky!
- Axios!（我是值得的！） - 拉斯基！
- Axios! - Lasky!
(speaking alien language)
(weapon fires)
(Growls)
No!
(creature howls)
(Growls)
拉斯基！拉斯基！
Lasky! Lasky!
拉斯基？
SULLY: Lasky?
拉斯基！
APRIL: Lasky!
Lasky!
拉斯基！
降落吧，凯莉
Bring it down, Kelly.
醒醒啊
- Come on. (coughing)
醒醒
Come on.
(Music)
(thrusters rumbling)
我们有3名幸存者
We have three survivors.
我已通知指挥部
WOMAN'S VOICE: I've alerted Command.
我们走
CHIEF: Let's go.
(Indistinct radio communications)
你们多大岁数？
How old are all of you?
机密
That's classified.
干得出色，士兵
Well done, soldier.
我还需要播放一遍吗，长官？
MALE COMPUTER VOICE: Shall I play it again, sir?
不用
No.
不需要了
That won't be necessary.
舰长下令进入紧急空间迁跃协议
MALE COMPUTER VOICE: The captain has moved us
into Emergency Slipspace Protocol.
准备低温生化休眠
Prepare for cryo.
UNSC 无尽号
（警告！不明航向更改，重力未定义，航速增加）
（重新启动）
（别走开，后面还有拍摄花絮）
(Music)
(sync marker beeps)
停
DIRECTOR: Cut.
(laughter)
拉斯基，快，我们走！
Lasky, come on, let's go!
(zipping)
(laughter)
拉斯基，拉斯基，我们走！
Lasky, Lasky, let's go!
拉斯基！拉斯基！
Lasky! Lasky!
(Bleep)
等下，老兄
Wait a minute, buddy.
好吧
TOM GREEN: Oh, okay.
多谢，拉斯基
Thanks, Lasky.
别担心
GREEN: No worries.
重新再向我吼吧
Go back to yelling at me.
警报
MAN: Alarm!
(laughing)
对不起啦，老兄
MAN: Sorry, man.
我不需要警告
I don't... I don't need the alarm.
重新来过，还在拍着呢
DIRECTOR: Back to one. Still rolling.
哔哔哔…
MAN: Beep beep... (laughing)
- 老兄，别搞嘛 - 重新来过
- Dude, come on, man. - Back to one.
透过窗外看到一个巨大的外星人
DIRECTOR: Okay, outside we see this massive alien
从那团烟里走出来
starting to stand up out of the smoke.
它很大，还在吼！
It's huge, it roars!
把雕塑切成两半
(laughter)
Smashes the statue in half!
Roar!
你喝高了吧
(laughing) You hopped. Your arm.
怎么了嘛？
(laughing)
快走！这里！
ANNA POPPLEWELL: What?
Go! Go! This way, this way!
这里，苏利文，快！
This way, Sullivan, go!
(laughter)
快！快！
Go! Go! Go!
啊！
Whaa! Aah!
噢，他妈的
Oh, for (bleep).
(laughter)
开始
DIRECTOR: Go.
老天
(laughing) Jeez.
有些东西海军情报处不想看我们
Something ONI wouldn't want to see us.
什么？
DIRECTOR: What now?
(laughter)
有些东西海军情报处不想看我们
Something ONI wouldn't want to see us.
是不想给我们看
Wouldn't want to show us.
是不想我们看到我们，等等
Wouldn't want us to see us. Wait.
是不想我们发现
Wouldn't want us to see.
海军情报处不想我们发现这些东西
Something ONI wouldn't want us to see.
(panting)
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Huh.
台词是啥？
What was the line?
噢
(Director speaks line) - Oh.
我好欣慰哦
I'm so thankful.
我们都感激涕零哦
We are so thankful.
你怎么找到我们的？
- How did you find us? (laughing)
等下
Wait.
托马斯，快点！
POPPLEWELL: Torn, hurry up!
嘿，凯勒，能帮我…
Hey, Chyler, can you get me...
(laughing)
Bffff!
(imitating gunfire)
KAT DE LIEVA: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Pfff! Pfff! Pfff!
Bag out!
嘘！
DE LIEVA: Shh!
(imitating gunfire)
嘘！
DE LIEVA: Shh.
嘘！轻点声
Shh! Not too loud.
(fork clangs on floor) (bleep)
别管它了
(laughter)
你们觉得那家伙是啥？
DIRECTOR: Don't worry about it.
What do you think that thing was?
嘿，JJ，你就不能放松下么？
Hey, JunJie, why don't you ease up?
不了，小苏，韦克斯是对的
Nah, Sully, Vickers is right.
再来一遍…
DIRECTOR: One more time...
(laughing)
干的好，凯勒
Well done, Chyler.
Axios!
能给我你的武器么？
Can you give me your weapon?
好吧
Oh, okay.
朝左转！
Left face!
(laughs)
快速…不好意思
Quick...(laughs) Sorry. Ahem.
为什么凯勒装配个活扳手
How the hell can Chyler put a monkey wrench together
远快过我…
faster than I can assemble a...
她6岁起就开始彩排这个了，老弟
GREEN: She's been acing these things since she was six, man.
我要重新来过
(laughs) I gotta go again.
麦哈非学员？
- Cadet Mehaffey? (bleep) (laughter)
还在拍呢
DIRECTOR: Still rolling.
为了你好，你最好能变出魔术
For your sake, you better be able to pull some magic out of that ass,
否则你…
or you'll be (bleep).
(laughter)
对不起啦！
Sorry!
这很隐私的
This is private, please.
(laughter)
军官上场，开拍！
DIRECTOR: Officer on deck. Action!
3，2，1，猎人登场！
DIRECTOR: Three, two, one, hunter!
士官长起身
Go, Chief.
3，2，1，开拍！
(laughing)
DIRECTOR: Three, two, one, action!
(stuntman laughing)
停
Cut!